### Contact

+91 8097456861 (Mobile) sidhanshu\_1988@yahoo.co.in

www.linkedin.com/in/sidhanshuudawat (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Android

Kotlin

Scala

### Languages

English (Full Professional)
German (Elementary)

Hindi (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Developing Your Emotional Intelligence

Preparing to Lead: Developing Mental Toughness in Yourself

Critical Thinking

# Sidhanshu Udawat

Senior Software Engineer at AutoScout24 Munich

## Summary

--- if you are a recruiter, please DO NOT waste your message credits on me since I'm not considering a move in any foreseeable future ---

I have hands on experience on many different parts of the flow and I love working on every aspect of the product which is from thinking about user experience to getting my hands dirty deep in code and challenging technical problems.

I use the following technology stack for Android Development:

- Kotlin for all new development and Java because of legacy code.
- I write code without side effects and which is testable.
- Android Jet Pack Components and have experience working on important components.
- MVVM and MVP
- Experience working on Reactive programming using RxAndroid / RxJava
- Git for source control.

My Git: https://github.com/SidhanshuUdawat?tab=repositories

# Experience

AutoScout24 Senior Software Engineer October 2018 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Munich, Bavaria, Germany

10 Digital Media
Lead Android Developer
June 2017 - July 2018 (1 year 2 months)
London, United Kingdom

Market i Software Specialist January 2016 - June 2017 (1 year 6 months) Dubai, United Arab Emirates

My work is all about creating "Amazing" Android Applications, perform research and development on various Technologies like OCR, Augmented Reality, location services, maps and even Google Glass.

To develop apps which cater to the latest Android OS as well as the old ones along with multiple screen sizes, multi lingual, dynamic, secured and reverse engineer proof.

Most important aspect of my job is to keep my self updated with the latest trends and technologies in IT world.

Tata Consultancy Services
Systems Engineer
August 2015 - January 2016 (6 months)
Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

#### **Atos**

Software Engineer March 2014 - August 2015 (1 year 6 months) Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

Zapak Digital Entertainment Limited Mobile Application Developer March 2013 - March 2014 (1 year 1 month) Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

i-XL Technologies
Mobile Games and Application Developer
June 2011 - March 2013 (1 year 10 months)
Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

Mobile Games and Application Developer using J2ME, Android and Blackberry Technologies

## Education

University of Mumbai

Bachelor of Science - B.Sc, Information Technology · (2008 - 2011)

Maharashtra State Board Of Technical Education
Diploma , Computer Engineering · (2004 - 2008)